

DAVID **BOTROS**

SENIOR DEVELOPER



CONTACT



Phone



Email



Address



Website







EDUCATION

Vorstudienlehrgang Mathematics & Physics

2016 - 2021 Bachelor Of Business



LANGUAGES

100%

Arabic

INTERESTS



ABOUT ME

I am a passionate, ambitious and hardworking developer, always trying to learn and improve myself. Furthermore, I consider myself a Team Player and creative in my approach to solve problems. A key strength of mine is communication; building strong relationship with people in order to deliver the best results. For the last 8 years I have been developing my skills by learning the coding standards and concepts, regardless of the language itself. I worked on different projects using different programming languages and frameworks, alone and in teams, in which I have learned how to collaborate on code, be consistent in my style of coding and how to maintain a code base of a project.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior React Native Developer @ MetaInfo-XR

Feb2023-Aug2023

- · Code base refactoring
- · Refactoring the architecture between frontend and backend
- Managed relations between customer and developers
- · Handling all junior's merge requests
- Helping Junior developers with their quests
- Holding workshops to explain the basic principles/ best practices of React

(2) **React Electron Developer** @ Rise

Apr2022-Nov2022

Worked as a frontend Developer using typescript & Electron framework. During the development i worked with Jira, confluence and GitLab.

Fullstack freelancer @Fiverr, UpWork

Apr2022-May2017

- · Designed the databank schema
 - Designed the architecture of the required system
 - · Created Api using Django restframework
 - · Created the UI using react and typescript

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript

TypeScript

Python

Advanced

Advanced

Advanced

FRAMEWORKS

React Native React

Next

Advanced

Advanced

Advanced

Django Rest Api Advanced

Electron Advanced